Joe Wojak

jwojak@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/joewojak https://github.com/jwwojak/jwwojak.github.io

I'm a technical writer with experience in creating documentation for external customers and internal engineering teams. My focus has been on ad tech, but expanded at Spotify to include a broad array of engineering topics. During my career, I've managed large, established documentation libraries and created content for new systems and services. My written work follows DITA standards for documentation. My writing philosophy is to treat documentation like code and keep content with the code.

Work Experience

Senior Technical WriterSpotify2017–2022Amplify R&DNew York City

- Wrote internal, developer-facing documentation for Amplify R&D, the free, ad supported part of Spotify.
- Documented company-wide systems and processes (e.g., Declarative Infrastructure, gRPC, GCS, Apollo).
- Created The Spotify Technical Writing Handbook, a writing and style guide for engineers.
- Wrote and revised "Golden Path" documentation, which are how-to tutorials for newly hired engineers.
- Used Loom to create videos on how to write and use Backstage (an internal documentation system).
- Created a writing guild to help coordinate and promote technical writing across Spotify.

Senior Technical Writer

Adobe Systems

2015-2017

Audience Manager

New York City

- Returned to Adobe to write external, customer-facing documentation for Audience Manager.
- Created and reorganized documentation for a new system, the Marketing Cloud ID Service.
- Created new documentation for another new system, the Marketing Cloud Device Co-Op.
- Helped API developers write API documentation for all the above services.
- Wrote and managed the bi-monthly release notes process.

Senior Technical Writer

Tapad

2013-2017

A SaaS, cross-device ad serving system

New York City

- First technical writer hired.
- Wrote customer-facing documentation for Tapad's probabilistic, cross-device ad targeting system.
- Worked with engineers to write API, Android, and iOS documentation.

Technical Writer

Demdex/Adobe Systems

2011-2013

Demdex was a NYC-based startup acquired by Adobe. The product was renamed Adobe Audience Manager.

- First technical writer hired.
- Wrote developer- and customer-facing documentation for Audience Manager.
- Migrated documentation from Google docs to Adobe's documentation system.

Education and Certifications

- MA, US History, University of Mississippi.
- BA (Magna Cum Laude), History, University of Missouri.

Writing Systems

• Methodology: Written work follows *Darwin Information Typing Architecture* (DITA) documentation standards.

• Technologies: HTML editors, DITA/XML systems (Oxygen, XMetaL), Markdown, GitHub, MkDocs.

• Others: Confluence, Coda, Loom (videos), LucidChart, Google (docs, slides, sheets), JIRA, Trello, Slack,

Illustrator, Visio.

Military Service

United States Army, Honorable Discharge.